Umut Öçgüder

Ankara, Türkiye

umutocgdr@gmail.com

00905074902605

linkedin.com/in/umutocguder

Summary

I'm using Swift and SwiftUI, Unit tests, Integration Tests, Leak Tests, TDD, ARC and memory management, offline storage (Core Data, User Defaults, Keychain Access, SQLite and Property List), 3rd party libraries (usually marketing and analytics), threading and performance tuning in Web Services, Network Caching, Error Handling, App Groups, Generics, Widgets(iOS 14+ SwiftUI), Modern Networking Layers(Async/Await), experience integrating with RESTful API backends, also, understanding of Apple's design principles and interface guidelines, familiarity with cloud messaging APIs and push notifications, Apple Frameworks, Core Animation, etc. MVVM, MVC, MVP, VIPER, Coordinator and Router.

I was born in 1999. I completed my compulsory military service. I took part in speeches on behalf of many companies in the Swift field.

Experience

Argelik iOS Developer

Arçelik Global

Sep 2023 - Present (7 months)

-HomeWhiz (iOT mobile app) [Swift 5 & MVVM] - iOS dev

https://www.homewhiz.com

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/homewhiz/id1234028528?I=tr



Softtech

Aug 2021 - Sep 2023 (2 years 2 months)

iOS development team member (scrum)

Projects:

-İşCep (Türkiye İş Bankası A.Ş. online banking application) [Swift - Objc] Over than 1.5M comments with a 4.6 star.

https://www.isbank.com.tr/iscep

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/i-%C5%9Fcep/id308261752

-İş Faktoring (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C] - lead iOS dev

https://www.isfaktoring.com.tr

-Fiba Faktoring (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C] - lead iOS dev

https://www.fibafaktoring.com.tr

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/fiba-faktoring/id6449927369?I=tr

-İşbank Iraq (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.isbank.iq

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/isbank-iraq-mobile/id1503186234

-İşbank Georgia (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

http://isbank.ge

Only available in Georgia

-İşbank London (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.isbank.co.uk

Only available in England

-İşbank Kosovo (fintech app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.isbankkosova.com

Only available in Kosovo

- -Kayra (swift component app) [Swift 5 | Swift UI]
- -Unluco (private banking app) [Swift 5 & MVC]
- -Triwi (women's health app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.triwi.info

Release canceled

Only package released by me:

-İşbank Germany (fintech app) [Flutter]

https://www.isbank.de

Only available in Germany

-İş Leasing (fintech app) [Quick]

https://www.isleasing.com.tr

Release canceled

Chance to analyze the code of:

-Nays (fintech app) [Swift UI & MVVM-C]

https://www.naysapp.com.tr

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/nays/id1602212505

-Lunafi (USA online banking app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.lunafi.co

Only available in USA

-Bayındır (hospital app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.bayindirhastanesi.com.tr

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/bay%C4%B1nd%C4%B1r-sa%C4%9FI%C4%B1k-grubu/id1505734810

-Paşabahçe (e-commerence app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.pasabahcemagazalari.com

https://apps.apple.com/tr/app/pa%C5%9Fabah%C3%A7e-ma%C4%9Fazalar%C4%B1/id1546075579

-ProEmtia (e-commerence app) [Swift 5 & MVVM-C]

https://www.proemtia.com

Not released yet



iOS Developer

AE Kod Teknolojisi - AE Yazılım

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

iOS development

https://aeyazilim.com

iOS Developer

Neva Mühendislik

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019 (4 months)

iOS development for Neva app.

Education

Selcuk University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

Sep 2017 - Aug 2021 Gpa: 3.19 / 4.00

Selcuk University, Faculty of Engineering (2017-2019)

The name of my university changed in 2019.

Konya Technical University, Faculty of Engineering and Natural Sciences (2019-2021)

Licenses & Certifications

Kodluyoruz Yemeksepeti Mobile iOS Bootcamp - Patika.dev

Google Entrepreneurship Course - Google

Mobile Programming - Komek

MEB0917502720190059584943

Softtech Entrepreneurship Course - Softtech

Skills

SwiftUI • Swift (Programming Language) • Swift • Internet of Things (IoT) • Agile Methodologies • iOS Development • Xcode • iOS • Mobile Application Development • Scrum

Honors & Awards

High Honor - KTUN

Jul 2021

8th semester average: 4.00/4.00

High Honor Student

Turkey Computer Engineering Students Congress Speaker - BİLMÖK

Jan 2022

https://www.bilmok.org

https://www.twitter.com/bilmok

https://www.instagram.com/bilmok.org.tr

100s Club Summit Speaker - 100s Club

Oct 2022

https://www.100sclub.com

https://www.twitter.com/100sClubtr

Cenga Computer Engineering Club Speaker - Cenga

Feb 2022

https://www.cenga.org

https://www.twitter.com/cengaorg/ https://www.instagram.com/cengaorg/

Ktun IT Community Speaker - Ktun IT Community

Dec 2023

https://www.ktun.edu.tr/tr/Birim/Hakkimizda?brm=c%200Ds5pW4T8fPMCw4epbqA%3D%3D

https://www.instagram.com/ktunbilisim/

https://www.linkedin.com/company/ktunbilisim/?originalSubdomain=tr